Guide to the Central Washington University Faculty Papers, Corinne Farrell Collection 1896–1988
Central Washington University Archives and Special Collections
Central Washington University Faculty Papers, Corinne Farrell Collection
1896-1988
Central Washington University, Archives and Special Collections 400 E University Way Ellensburg, WA 98926 (509) 963-1717 http://www.lib.cwu.edu/Archives-Special-Collections archive@cwu.edu
FP-0006
Farrell, Corinne
5 cubic feet 4 letter size boxes, 1 half-letter size box, 2 oversize boxes, 2 record center boxes Personal papers, personal artifacts, photographs, professional publications, framed pictures in good condition
This collection consists of materials relating to the personal life and professional career of Corinne Farrell, former professor at Central Washington University.
Biographical Note
Corinne Farrell was born in Ellensburg, Washington in 1924. She graduated from Ellensburg High School in 1942 and earned bachelor's degrees from the University of Washington and Central Washington College of Education. She went on to earn a medical degree from Creighton University in Omaha, Nebraska, in 1957 and eventually became Professor of Radiology at the University of Missouri-Columbia, where she was active in bone cancer research. She returned to Central Washington University in 1985 as a research professor.
This collection consists of Corinne Farrell's personal correspondence, educational and professional certificates, newspaper clippings, professional research publications, trapshooting trophies, medical equipment, and photographs.
Central Washington University began as the Washington State Normal School in 1891. In 1937, the school was rechristened the Central Washington College of Education. In 1961, the school became Central Washington State College and, finally, in 1977, Central Washington University.
Organized by series. Arranged chronologically within series.
Open to the public for educational research.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Farrell, Corinne
Central Washington University, Biological Sciences Department
Ellensburg (Wash.)
Universities & colleges--United States; Biology--Research--United States
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
Educators
- Personal Papers
  - The Dawn Populist Newspaper, 1896 (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Ellensburg Theatre Petition, 1905 (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Lundeen War Speech, 1917 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Pearl Dixon’s Normal School Diplomas, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Birth Certificates, 1924 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Correspondence from Grandfather, 1944 (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1946-1969 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Leather Photo Album with Pictures, 1944 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Trapshooting Newspaper Articles, 1951 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Father’s Memorial Record, 1951 (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Correspondence from Mother, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 1-11)
  - Continuing Education Certificates, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 1-12)
  - Professional Certifications and Educational Achievements, 1957-1987 (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Alumni Association Report, 1958 (Box-folder 1-14)
  - Correspondence from Mother, 1959 (Box-folder 1-15)
  - Licensing Correspondence and Applications, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - Correspondence from Mother, 1960-1964 (Box-folder 2-2)
  - Press and Publicity, 1968-1980 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Outstanding Alumni Award, 1969 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - International Biography, 1973 (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Organizational Newsletters, 1973-1987 (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Professional Licenses and Certificates, 1975-1983 (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Passport Application, 1979 (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Erwin Klink, Jr. Letters and Dissertation Chapters, 1980 (Box-folder 2-9)
  - Erwin Klink, Jr. Dissertation and Approval, 1981 (Box-folder 2-10)
  - Erwin Klink, Jr. Resume and Letter, 1982 (Box-folder 2-11)
  - Medical Forms, 1982 (Box-folder 2-12)
  - List of Donations to UMC Health Science Library, 1983 (Box-folder 2-13)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1983 (Box-folder 2-14)
  - UMC Faculty Recognition Award Program, 1984 (Box-folder 2-15)
  - Bone Library Donation Tax Appraisal Summary, 1988 (Box-folder 2-16)
  - Faculty Library Display, 1988 (Box-folder 2-17)
  - Scrapbook, Miscellaneous, 1944-1970 (Box-folder 2-18)
  - Scrapbook, Newspaper Clippings, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 2-19)
  - Scrapbook, Scholarship Donations, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 2-20)
  - Letter from Father (Box-folder 2-21)
  - Correspondence to Pearl Farrell (Box-folder 2-22)
  - Grandfather’s Obituary (Box-folder 2-23)
  - Image of Thomas W. Farrell (Box-folder 2-24)
  - Leather Pocket Book (Box-folder 2-25)
- Professional Papers
  - Western Orthopedic Association Meeting Presentation, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Osteosarcoma Publication and Address, 1964 (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Duodenal Duplication Publication, 1965 (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Miscellaneous Bone Publications, 1965-1986 (Box-folder 3-4)
  - List of Publications, 1968-1986 (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Osteosarcoma in Hamsters Publications, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 3-6)
  - Radiation Therapy for Treatment of Osteosarcoma, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 3-7)
  - Thermography Publications and Research, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 3-8)
  - Parosteal Sarcoma Publications, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 3-9)
  - Thermography and Osteosarcoma Publications, 1968 (Box-folder 3-10)
  - Pathological Fractures in Osteosarcoma, 1969 (Box-folder 3-11)
  - Electron Spin Resonance (ESR) Publications, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 3-12)
  - Thermography and Metastatic Liver Disease Publications, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3-13)
  - Computer Assisted Research Publications, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 3-14)
  - Evidence for a Human Osteosarcoma Virus, 1971 (Box-folder 3-15)
  - Thermography and Pediatrics Publication, 1972 (Box-folder 3-16)
  - Thermography and Metastatic Breast Cancer Publications, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 3-17)
  - Mid-America Bone Diagnostic Center, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 3-18)
  - Bone Tumor Lesions Research, 1973 (Box-folder 4-1)
  - Bone Case of the Month Publications, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 4-2)
  - Breast Cancer Research and Publications, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 4-3)
  - Effect of Film Miniaturization on Diagnostic Accuracy, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 4-4)
  - Radiology Publications, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 4-5)
  - Paget’s Disease of Bone Publications, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 4-6)
  - Skeletal Radiology Publications, 1981 (Box-folder 4-7)
  - Osteosarcoma and Hodgkin’s Disease Publications, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 4-8)
  - Desmoplastic Fibroma of Bone Publications, 1986 (Box-folder 4-9)
  - Osteoid Osteoma Publications, 1986 (Box-folder 4-10)
  - UMC Bone Library Donation Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 4-11)
  - Research Facts and Figures (Box-folder 4-12)
  - Thermographic Findings in Inflammatory Breast Cancer (Box-folder 4-13)
  - CAD Breast Disease Publication (Box-folder 4-14)
  - Unpublished Paper on Osteosarcoma (Box-folder 4-15)
  - Doctoral Thesis, First Half (Box-folder 5-1)
  - Doctoral Thesis, Second Half (Box-folder 5-2)
- Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 6)
- Diplomas
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 7)
  - Framed Birth Announcements (Box 7)
- Artifacts
  - Trophies (Box 8)
  - Medical Bag (Box 8)
  - Trapshooter’s Vest with Medals (Box 8)
  - White Medical Coat (Box 8)
  - Glasses with Cases (Box 8)
  - Tuning Fork (Box 8)
  - Knee Knockers (Box 8)
  - Personal Stamp (Box 8)
  - Pins (Box 8)
  - Rosary (Box 8)
  - Framed Family Photos (Box 9)
  - Trapshooting Award (Box 9)